Select a language

International schoolsUK editionAustralia edition

* Open [School solutions](https://www.edukey.co.uk/en-gb/for-schools)
    
    * Pupil and learning management

        * [Tes Parents' Meetings Parents' evenings system that works for everyone](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/for-schools/parents-meetings)

        * [Tes Clubs and Events Look after extracurricular life with Tes Clubs and Events](https://www.edukey.co.uk/en-gb/for-schools/clubs-and-events)

    * Safeguarding and compliance

    * Staff management & Finance
        
        * [Staff Management Subscription Recruitment, training and wellbeing solutions in one all-inclusive subscription](https://www.edukey.co.uk/en-gb/for-schools/staff-management)

Open Menu

TES Close

* [School solutions](https://www.edukey.co.uk/en-gb/for-schools) Open
    
    * [Pupil and learning management](https://www.tes.com/) Open

    * Safeguarding and compliance Open

    * Staff management & Finance Open

Select a language

International schoolsUK editionAustralia edition

Privacy Notice
==============

LAST UPDATED 06 JUNE 2024 Open all

Latest Changes to this Policy

27/04/2023: Page design was updated.

08/03/2023: Updated company address in the Privacy Notice and section 9.

31/10/2022: Updated section 3 to include reference to Pendo. Updated section 9 to remove an email address.

30/06/2022: Updated title name from Privacy Policy to Privacy Notice, amended introduction, added information on Privacy Act 1988 (**Cth**). Links to different data protection jurisdictions included where appropriate in the Notice. The legal basis of processing personal information amended in Section 2. Added information regarding Standard Contractual Clauses in section 5. Amended contact information in section 9.

List of data processors, mainly critical third-party vendors that holds user data included in section 3.

01/04/2022: Updated section 4 of the policy to include reference to the use of Google reCAPTCHA on this site.

15/06/2021: Updated section 3 of the policy to include reference to the new chargeback investigation process which may include the sharing of personal data with third parties. 

27/05/2021: Updated the contact details for our EU Representative in section 10. 

21/05/2021: Updated references to the GDPR with the UK GDPR. Included a link to the Tes Institute Privacy Policy. Included contact details for European Data Subjects to use when contacting us with enquires. 

21/12/2020: Updated section 4 with relevant information related to the payment of royalties to Authors using the Tes Resources Marketplace;

12/11/2020: Updated references to processing for the Blendspace product following its transfer to Mas Espacio Blancio Inc. 

27/08/2020: Added link to specific Privacy Policy for Tes Develop product. 

03/07/2020: Updated sections 3 and 5 to include more information on the use of MyCV information when users have opted-in to machine lead and human red recruitment services. 

updated section 3 to provide better information about how Tes uses personal data when investigating potential discrimination on our platform. 

27/05/2020: Included reference to the Covid 19 Back to School Hub Update. 

17/04/2020: Updated sections 3 and 4 of this Policy to provide detail on Data Processing and Data Sharing in the event that a product or service provided by Tes is transferred to a new organisation and that organisation becomes a Data Controller for information processed about you. 

Read more Read less

Privacy Notice

Tes Global Limited ("**we**", "**our**" or "**Tes**") is committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals in respect of whom we hold personal information. Tes includes our trading activities that are branded Tes.

Please take your time to read this Privacy Notice ("**Notice**”) which explains how we use and protect your personal information. This Notice applies to the use of all our services and websites (and web-based services) on which a link to this Notice appears (the "**Sites**").

Tes is a private limited company registered in England, company number 02017289 with its registered address at Building 3 St Pauls Place, Norfolk Street, Sheffield, England, S1 2JE, United Kingdom.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Laws, the Data Protection Act 2018 (“**DPA 2018**”), and the UK General Data Protection Regulation (“**UK GDPR**"), the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (“**PECR**”), and the Privacy Act 1988 (**Cth**), the EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (“**EU** **GDPR**”), and any other applicable data protection laws. Tes Global is a Data Controller.

We take your privacy seriously and we are committed to keeping your information private. To the extent we are required by law, we have notified the United Kingdom's Information Commissioner's Office that we will process your personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Legislation (as defined above) and other Supervisory Authorities.

By providing us with your information (including via the Sites), you understand that we will process your personal information in accordance with this Notice and our Cookie Policy [here](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/policies/cookies-policy).

Read more Read less

This Privacy Notice covers

1. What personal information we collect about you and how we collect it.
2. Legal basis for collecting and using your personal information.
3. Personal information we share with third parties. 
4. Automated processing, including tracking and profiling.
5. Data retention, data security and data transfers. 
6. Your Rights.
7. How to unsubscribe from email alerts that you receive. 
8. Changes to this Privacy Notice.
9. Talk to us.

Read more Read less

1\. What personal information we collect about you and how we collect it

**1.1 Information that you provide us directly**

We collect personal information when you contact us, and we can identify you from the information you have provided. This can be done when you contact us by phone, email, live chat or when you sign up to use any of our services including but not limited to when:

1. You register and create a Tes ID user account;
2. Post content on any of our Sites (such as on any forums or chatrooms);
3. Upload your CV;
4. Purchase a product from us (such as through the Tes Store);
5. Subscribe to receive a product or service that we offer (for example, a magazine subscription);
6. Subscribe to receive email updates from us;
7. Take part in a competition or market research and every time you e-mail us directly; and
8. You make a payment or perform a transaction with us. 

**1.2 Content posted by you containing personal information**

If you post any personal information to any of our public forums, this information will immediately be made available to other users throughout the world who may use it to contact you.

In some circumstances, we may display an alias that you choose that identifies you as a user but does not use your personal information. An example of this is your username or your Tes ID.

**1.3 Information that we automatically collect (including the use of "cookies")**

We automatically collect limited information about your visits to our Sites. This includes demographic data and browsing patterns. The information we collect includes your: IP address (which identifies the computer or device that you use to access the Sites); the time and date of your visit; browser; operating system; internet connection details, as well as a breakdown of your journey through our Sites and products that you searched for. These cookies are used for user experience, analytic purposes, social media feed, and advertising our products, assessing potentially fraudulent or other criminal activities and auditing usage of the Sites. 

You can opt out of all cookies except necessary cookies which makes our Sites usable.  

**1.4 Use of Cookies**

We use cookies to collect your personal information. A cookie is a small text file/information stored in your machine that can be retrieved by us. These small pieces of information consist of letters and numbers that allow us to collect information about you.

The use of cookies may allow registered users to be presented with a personalised version of the Sites.

Our Sites use external ad servers (such as "DoubleClick") to serve the advertisements that you see on pages from our Sites. They use cookies to collect information about your use of our Sites to help target ads to your interests. To find out more about the use of cookies by DoubleClick, please see [here](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/enterprise/).  

Please note that if you disable specific cookies, certain services on our Sites may not be available to you. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use products or services that require you to "sign-in" and you may not be able to take full advantage of offerings or use them on all our Sites.

For further information please see our Cookies Policy [here](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/policies/cookies-policy) and for more independent information about cookies please see [here](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

**1.5 Information that we collect from third parties**

Third parties of Tes may provide us with information relating to you. It is that third party's responsibility to ensure that it has obtained your consent to do this. However, where possible, we will request from our third party that they have the right to pass on this information.

Read more Read less

2\. Legal basis for collecting and using your personal information

Data Protection Laws mandate that personal information can only be used where there is a lawful basis to do so. At Tes, we rely on one or more legal basis to collect and use your personal information where:

1. The information is necessary for the performance of the contract.
2. We are using your personal information for our legitimate interests.
3. We have a legal obligation to process your personal information.
4. You have consented to the use of your personal information.

Where we rely on your consent to process your personal information, you can amend your email preferences at any time by logging into your account [here](https://www.tes.com/authn/select?rtn=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tes.com%2Fpreference-centre%2F).

**2.1 Performance of a Contract**

We will use your personal information for the following purposes where it is necessary to perform a contract or enter into a contract with you. This includes but not limited to:

1. To authenticate your identity and administer your Tes ID user account.
2. To deal with your enquiries, requests, and purchases.
3. To provide MyCV, Job Alert and the Quick Apply service and share with recruitment institutions where you have signed up for this service.
4. To enter you into competitions or prize draws upon your request.
5. To enable our data processors provide you with products and services requested by you. 

**2.2 Legitimate Interest**

We may use your personal information where we have a legitimate business interest to do so. This includes but is not limited to:

1. To personalise aspects of our services to you.
2. To carry out market research, surveys, anonymise or archive data about our products and services.
    
3. For marketing and strategic development purposes.
4. For the proper keeping of business records.
5. To provide you with updates about developments on the Sites.

**2.3 Legal Obligation**

We will use your personal information where we are legally obliged to do so, this includes but is not limited to:

1. Financial reporting and auditing purposes.
2. Where you work with us, or we place you in a job.
3. For anti-money laundering or fraud prevention, detection, and reporting.
4. To maintain records of actions taken on your account.

**2.4 Consent**

We will use your personal information where we have your consent to do so:

1. To provide you with direct marketing information related to information about the products and services we offer.
2. To contact you about job opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you.

Where you have provided us with your consent, we may use your personal information to enable data processors to contact you in relation to the services offered in conjunction with us or in respect of the services that they provide. 

You can amend your email preferences at any time by logging into your account [here](https://www.tes.com/authn/select?rtn=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tes.com%2Fpreference-centre%2F). It is your responsibility to ensure that any information you submitted as part of the registration process to your Tes ID user account or as part of a job application is accurate and up to date.

For more information on the legal basis we rely upon in processing your personal information in different data protection jurisdictions,

1. For the UK or the EEA, click [here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/).
2. For Australia, click [here](https://assets.tes.com/content-attachments/s3fs-public/media/file/2022-03/Australia_Privacy_Act%201988.pdf).
3. For Hong Kong, click [here](https://www.dataguidance.com/notes/hong-kong-data-protection-overview).

Read more Read less

3\. Personal information we share with third parties

To provide the services offered on our Sites, we sometimes need to share your personal information with other companies operating as Tes. However, we will continue to be responsible for the usage and security of your personal information when this happens. 

Tes critical third-party vendors are:

1. 8x8, INC.
2. Amazon.com, Inc.
3. Dotdigital Group PLC.
4. Drupal.
5. Fastly, Inc.
6. Freshworks, Inc.
7. Microsoft Corporation.
8. Mimecast Services Ltd.
9. Salesforce.
10. Mailgun Technologies.
11. Alphabet Inc. (Google).
12. Groupcall.
13. Wonde.
14. Pure Cyber.
15. Concentrix Catalyst Limited.
16. Zoho Corporation.
17. Oracle Corporation.
18. Bullhorn, Inc.
19. Zoom Video Communications, Inc.
20. Pendo.

**3.1 Tes' data processors**

We may share your personal information with third-party processors or suppliers that we engage with to provide you with products and services you required (such as our hosting providers). These third parties may need to process your personal information on our behalf to provide such services. Where this is the case, we take great care to only engage reliable third parties who can guarantee the security of your personal information and our business information.

To protect your personal information, every third party we engage with completes a due diligence questionnaire to ensure their practices and procedures provide a reasonable level of security that we would expect (and is required under the data protection laws) when processing personal information. 

**3.2 Third parties that we share your personal information with** 

Where a legal basis of processing applies, we may share your personal information with data processors (who may also be data controllers in respect of the information that we share). Some of our Sites and services are hosted by Tes on behalf of recruitment institutions that have signed up to process job vacancies and applications via [here](https://www.tes.com/for-schools/portal).

If you have any concerns about how your personal information is handled, you must get in touch with your institution as they may be data controllers for your personal information.

In any event that Tes decides to sell or transfer a product or service which we provide to you, or to an organisation whom you work for, we may transfer a subset of your data to them to ensure you can continue to access that product and service uninterrupted. Prior to the transfer of your data, we will contact you with the third-party details. We will give you reasonable opportunity to opt-out sharing your data with the third party. 

**3.3 Other circumstances where we use or share your personal information**

In certain circumstances, we may be required by law to disclose your personal information to government agencies and other organisations such as law enforcement agencies, banks or other financial institutions and data protection regulators.

We use Google reCAPTCHA on this Site. This service is used to check whether the data you have entered on our Sites (such as on a contact form) has been entered by a human or by an automated program. To do this, reCAPTCHA analyses the behaviour of your Sites visit based on various characteristics. The analysed data is collected by Google. For more information about Google reCAPTCHA please see Google's privacy policy [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB). 

Read more Read less

4\. Automated processing, including tracking and profiling

**4.1 Opting in to be contacted about job opportunities**

Where you have opted in to be contacted about jobs opportunities, the personal information you have provided regarding your experience, qualifications and job interests will be used alongside your Site activity to match you to relevant roles.

The purpose of this is to provide a limited, but accurate and appropriate data set of your information to schools using services like SmartMatch Direct for recruitment purposes and to ensure that you are only contacted about roles relevant to you.

The school will make contact with potential candidates via Tes using the information above, including but not limited to your name and contact details.

If you would not like to be matched with jobs, untick the box found in the career preferences section on your profile. You can amend your email preferences at any time by logging into your account [here](https://www.tes.com/authn/select?rtn=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tes.com%2Fpreference-centre%2F).

Read more Read less

5\. Record Retention, Data Security and Data Transfer

Record retention is necessary for our operational business purposes and in some cases required to fulfil statutory, regulatory, and/ or contractual obligations.

We will only keep your personal information for as long as they serve a useful business purpose or until all legal and regulatory requirements are met. This means we will retain personal information for the duration of any contract we have with you, in line with any legal obligation for record retention (such as that for HMRC, Ofsted) or until erasure is requested by you.

The transmission of personal information via the internet is not completely secured. We will take reasonable steps to protect your personal information in line with our internal processes, however, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted via email and/or our website; any transmission is at your own risk. 

The personal information that we collect from you will, where possible, be stored in the United Kingdom (the UK), the European Economic Area (the EEA) or Australia. In certain circumstances, we may require third parties that are based outside of the UK or the EEA to process, host or store your personal information. By submitting your personal information to us, you acknowledge this processing, storage, or transfer.

Please note that countries in other jurisdictions may not have the same standard of data protection laws in the UK or countries the EEA.   

In the event your personal information is processed or stored outside of the UK or the EEA, we will take all reasonable and necessary steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Notice and applicable Data Protection Laws. 

1. We will only allow third parties to access your personal information where: They are in countries that have been confirmed by the European Commission to provide an adequate level of protection for your data subjects’ rights and freedoms;
2. They have appropriate safeguards are in place such as Binding Corporate Rules or Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission and/ or ICO;
3. There is a Data Sharing Agreement in place that allows us to transfer personal information between our subsidiaries, at present, Tes has Data Sharing Agreements in place with its subsidiaries in Australia, the US, and Hong Kong;
4. They have agreed to provide all protections to your personal information as set out in the Data Protection Laws (such as by entering into the European Commission's Model Clauses). 

Read more Read less

6\. Your Rights

You have the right to ask Tes to uphold one or more of your Data Subject Rights:

1. You can ask to access the personal information we hold about you;
2. Make changes to ensure that any personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date;
3. Erase or restrict the processing of any personal information we hold about you where a legal basis is no longer applies; or
4. Transfer any information we hold about you to a specified third party. 

If you have any queries or complaints in relation to how we use your personal information, please contact us via the details set out in section 9 below. 

Where Tes is not a data controller, you should contact the institution in the first instance.

If you are not satisfied with the way your Data Subject Rights have been handled, you have the right to contact the Information Commissioner's Office via [here](https://ico.org.uk/) or by telephoning 0303 123 1113.

Read more Read less

7\. How to unsubscribe from any email alerts that you receive

If you have consented to receive marketing communication from us, these products or services can be offered jointly with or on behalf of a third party and/or "alerts" from us via email (for example, by creating an email alert for a job).

If at any time, you want to unsubscribe from these services, click on the "**unsubscribe**" link at the bottom of an email, amend your email preferences by logging into your account [here](https://www.tes.com/authn/select?rtn=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tes.com%2Fpreference-centre%2F) or please email us at [help@tes.com](mailto:help@tes.com).

Read more Read less

8\. Changes to this Privacy Notice

Tes may amend this Notice at any time. Where and when we make material changes to this Notice, we will provide updates on our website.

It is your responsibility to ensure that you are aware of the latest version of this Notice and by continuing to use our services and/or our Sites, request services from us or otherwise engage with us, you will be deemed to have accepted the updated Notice.

If you do not agree to any changes that we make, you should not use or access (or continue to use or access) our services and/or our Sites.

Read more Read less

9\. Talk to us

The registered office of Tes Global Limited is:

Building 3 St Pauls Place, Norfolk Street, Sheffield, England, S1 2JE, United Kingdom

**If you live in the EEA**, please contact our EU Representative:

Postal Address: The DPO Centre Europe, Alexandra House, 3 Ballsbridge Park, Dublin, D04C 7H2, Ireland.

Telephone: +353 1 631 9460.

We will use all reasonable efforts to answer any questions or resolve any concerns regarding your privacy promptly.

All comments, queries and requests relating to our use of your personal information are welcomed. If you would like to contact us, all queries should be addressed to our Customer Services at the above address; or by email at [help@tes.com](mailto:help@tes.com).

Read more Read less

Back to top

* [About](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/corporate) Open

* [Jobs](https://www.tes.com/jobs/) Open

* [Magazine](https://www.tes.com/magazine) Open

* [Resources](https://www.tes.com/teaching-resources) Open

* [Tes Institute](https://www.tes.com/institute) Open

* [Advice Hub](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/advice-hub) Open

* [Products](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/for-schools) Open

* [Products](https://www.tes.com/en-gb/for-schools) Open

Copyright © 2024

This website and its content is subject to our [General Terms of Business](https://www.tes.com/policies/general-terms-business). Tes Global Ltd is registered in England (Company No 02017289) with its registered office at Building 3, St Paul’s Place, Norfolk Street, Sheffield, S1 2JE.
